mtatva.com 2014-04-23

# Welcome to mTatva

## mTatva Services Usage and Privacy Statement

mTatva is committed to protecting your privacy. This privacy statement applies to the data collected by mTatva through the mTatva Account (the "Service"). It does not apply to data collected by other online or offline mTatva sites, products, or services. 

### Introduction

The Service is a personal health platform that lets you gather, edit, add to, store, and share health information online. With the Service, you can control your own health records. You can also share your health information with family, friends, health care professionals, mobile phone applications, health-related devices, and online tools.   
You can store health information for other people (such as your family) in one patient account. You should store and access each person's information in separate health records within your account.   
You can choose to share information with separate programs and systems that can connect with the Service ("Programs") to use, edit and add to your health record. Programs can help you manage your information and find relevant health information.   
You can choose to share specific information (or all information) with: 

  * other people (such as friends and family)
  * Programs (such as Programs that add data to your health records, provide information to your healthcare provider, or use some of your health records to provide information to you about managing your health)

### Collection of your personal information

The Service asks you to enter an identifier and password to sign in. The Service currently accepts mTatva account credentials.   
mTatva account is a service that allows you to sign into mTatva products, web sites and services, as well as those of select mTatva partners. If user do not already have a mTatva account, we will create a mTatva account for you at the same time you open your account. To create a mTatva account, mTatva sends certain information (but no health information) about you to the mTatva account system. When you sign into a site or service using your mTatva account, mTatva collects certain information in order to verify your identity on behalf of the site or service, to protect you from malicious mTatva account usage, and to protect the efficiency and security of the mTatva account service. We also send certain information to a site or service you have signed into with your mTatva account.   
The first time you sign in to the Service, the Service asks you to create a mTatva account. To create a mTatva account, you must provide personal information such as name, date of birth, e-mail address, postal code and country/region. Depending on which features you use, you may be asked for additional information for that feature (such as creating an emergency profile or fitness goal).   
We will use the e-mail address and mobile number you provide when you create your mTatva account to send you an e-mail and/or sms requesting that you validate your email address, to include in sharing invitations you send through the Service and to send you Service notifications, such as e-mail notification that information is available to add to your patient records. As described in their privacy statements, Programs you authorize may also use your e-mail address.   
A mTatva account allows you to manage one or more health records, such as the ones you create for yourself and your family members. You choose what information to put in your records. Examples of the types of information you can store in a record include: 

  * fitness-related activities such as aerobic sessions
  * measurements such as blood glucose and blood pressure
  * discharge summaries from hospitalizations
  * paper prescriptions
  * lab results
  * medications
  * health history
  * custom pictures related to health

You can use Programs to enter a wide range of health information into a record. You can give Programs permission to view, add, modify, and/or delete information in a record. Some Programs store their own copy of the information they access. The Service may provide links to each Program's privacy statements at the time the Service asks you to authorize the Program's access. Please read those for information such as where and how the Program may use, store and transfer your information; what additional information it may collect; how you can review, edit and delete the information it holds; and other choices you may have. You can also store files, and can add or edit some information directly when logged into your Service account. 

#### Other information we collect

To help operate and improve the service, we also collect information about how you interact with our services, including the browser you're using, your IP address, location, cookies or other unique IDs, the pages you visit and features you use. We combine this with other users’ information to get an overall view of how the service is used. 

### Sharing your personal health information

By default, you are the custodian of any records you create. You may invite additional people to be custodians. Each custodian can add and remove other custodians and users who can view and modify the record. Some of the information stored in the records you manage may be highly sensitive, so you need to consider carefully with whom you choose to share the information. A record may have multiple custodians.   
A key value of the Service is the ability to share your health information with people and services who can help you meet your health-related goals. For example, you can share health information from records you control: 

  * to co-manage the health of a family member
  * to use it with other health-related products and services
  * to consult with your health care provider
  * to provide fitness information to coaches and trainers

You can share information in a health record you are custodian of with another person by sending a sharing invitation e-mail through the Service. If the person accepts your sharing invitation and has or creates a Service account, you have given him or her access to that information. You can specify how long they have access (custodian access does not expire but, like all sharing access, it can be revoked at any time) and whether they can modify the information in the record. Each person who accepts a sharing invitation can grant Programs the same level of access that the person has.   
You can also choose to grant custodian access to other persons, such as your spouse, for any record of which you are a custodian. Custodian access is the broadest level of access, so you should think carefully before you grant custodian access to a record. Every custodian of a record has the same access to the record, including accessing, modifying, deleting, and sharing all the information in the record. A custodian can also revoke access to a record from any other custodian of the record, including you.   
You can also share personal information and health information with Programs. You decide which Programs you want to use. You must approve (or deny) the Program's access. The access request will include (a) the type of information the Program will access, (b) generally what the Program wants to do with the information (view, add, modify), and (c) links to more detailed information from the Program about its legal terms and privacy practices. You can find some Programs listed at mTatva.com and you can access Programs directly through their own Web sites. A user who has the appropriate level of access must affirmatively authorize a Program's access to any health record in your account. mTatva requires Program providers to agree to provide accurate information about their privacy practices and comply with applicable laws.However, except for restricting the access they have to your mTatva data we do not control or monitor the practices of those Programs, and their privacy practices will vary. You can read the Program's privacy statement for more information. You can freely grant and revoke a Program's access to the records stored in the Service. The access you grant a Program through the Service is valid until you revoke that access.   
Service users with whom you have shared your records can also give a Program access to those records. You can see a complete history of how Programs have accessed the information in your records by using the History feature in the record.   
Anyone (including someone who is not a custodian) who has access to a record can create and print a wallet card that contains a summary of the emergency profile information they have access to, and can create an access code. If an access code is created, it will be on the wallet card. Anyone who knows the access code can use it at our web site to view the emergency profile information stored on the record. Service users should protect wallet cards and access codes to guard against inappropriate use. Each time an access code is used at our web site to view the emergency profile information stored on a record, we will log it in the record history and we will notify by email the record user who created the access code, but we will not know who used the access code. Whoever has the access code can use it, and may pass it along to others who can also use it, until the access code is cancelled. Only the user who created the access code can cancel that access code. The record user can cancel the access code by signing into the Service and following the instructions. You can see a history of the creation and cancellation of access codes in the record history. 

### How we use your personal information

We use personal information collected through the Service, including health information, to provide the Service, and as described in this privacy statement. We do not use or disclose your information except as described in this privacy statement.   
In support of these uses, mTatva may use personal information: 

  * to provide you with important information about the Service, including critical updates and notifications
  * to send you various services over sms, call or email as described in feature statement. You will have options to opt-out of the service but by default you agree that we can send you necessary alerts and messages. 
  * to send you the mTatva e-mail newsletter if you opt-in
  * to determine your age and location to help determine whether you qualify for an account or for service features such as which language version or Program directory to display

mTatva occasionally hires other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, such as answering customer questions about products and services. We give those companies only the personal information they need to deliver the service, such as IP address or e-mail address. mTatva requires the companies to maintain the confidentiality of the information and prohibits them from using the information for any other purpose.   
mTatva may access and/or disclose your personal information if we believe such action is necessary to: (a) comply with the law or respond to legal process served on mTatva; or (b) protect the rights or property of mTatva (including the enforcement of our agreements). 

### Why we access health records

Our clinical team accesses the prescription anonymously to digitize the information into EMR. This is needed as part of the service we offer to patients on our portal. 

### How we use aggregate information and statistics

mTatva may use aggregated information from the Service to improve the quality of the Service and for marketing of the Service. This aggregated information is not associated with any individual account. mTatva does not use your individual mTatva account and record information from the Service for marketing without mTatva first asking for and receiving your opt-in consent. 

### Service access and controls

You choose whether to create an account with the Service. The required mTatva account information consists of a small amount of information such as your name, e-mail address, region, and Service credentials. We may request other optional information, but we clearly indicate that such information is optional. You can review and update your account information. You can modify, add, or delete any optional mTatva account information by signing into the Service and editing your account profile.   
You can close your mTatva account at any time by signing into the Service and editing your account profile. We wait 90 days before permanently deleting your mTatva account information in order to help avoid accidental or malicious removal of your health information.   
When you close your mTatva account, the Service deletes all records for which you are the sole custodian. If you share custodian access for a record, you can decide whether to delete the record from the Service. You should think carefully before you grant custodian access to your records.   
If you close your mTatva account or lose your account credentials, you may not be able to regain access to your Service information. 

### Record access and controls

The Service allows an account to contain multiple health records. This feature enables, for example, family health managers to create and manage records for family members.   
When you create a record, you become a custodian of that record. As a custodian, you decide what level of access to grant other users of the Service or Programs. The Service creates a fixed list of each access or change by Programs and users, which the Service keeps as a full history of the record. You can view and update records you are custodian of and can examine the history of access and changes to those records. 

#### Sharing records with other Service users

The level of access you can grant as a custodian include: 

  * View-only access (time-limited access)
  * View-and-modify access (time-limited access)
  * Custodian access (no time limit)

Access becomes active only when the recipient accepts the invitation.   
Custodian access is the highest level of access. A custodian of a health record can: 

  * Read the record
  * Change the record
  * Delete the record
  * Grant to others any level of access to the record, including custodian access
  * Revoke the access of anyone to a record, including other custodians, and including the custodian who granted them custodian access in the first place

Because inappropriate granting of access could allow a grantee to violate your privacy or even revoke your access to your own records, we urge you to consider all the consequences carefully before you grant access to your records.   
When you grant someone non-custodian access, that person can grant the same level of access to Programs (for example, someone with view-only access can grant a Program view-only access).   
As explained in the section titled "Sharing your personal health information" above, a custodian (or anyone who has access to a record) can create access codes that can be used by anyone to get view-only access at our web site to emergency profile information stored in the record, until the access code is cancelled by the record user who created the access code. 

#### Sharing records with programs through the Service

We provide you with information from the providers of various Programs that can connect with the Service. Programs may store or process health information in other countries or regions of the world. You should view information from the Programs, including their privacy statements and terms of use, prior to using them or allowing them access to any of your health information.   
In order to access the Service, the Program provider must agree to provide accurate information about its privacy practices and comply with applicable laws. mTatva can revoke a Program provider's access to the Service if a Program does not meet its privacy commitments to mTatva. However, except for restricting the access they have to your mTatva data, we do not control or monitor those Programs, and their privacy practices will vary. We encourage you to contact us if you believe a Program is not protecting the privacy or security of your health data.   
No Program has access to your information through the Service unless and until an authorized user opts in through the Service to grant it access. You control what health information you allow Programs to access and the length of time they can access the information in the record. If a Program requires information you are uncomfortable sharing, you can choose not to authorize that Program access to the record. A Program you authorize for a record will get the full name associated with your mTatva account, the nickname of the authorized record(s), and your relationship to that record. The Service allows you to control (by accepting or denying Program requests for access) which health information types in a specific health record you choose to share with each Program and what actions you allow each Program to perform on the health information. 

### Deleting records

You can delete any health record that you are a custodian of by signing in to your mTatva account and editing a record's profile. If other users had any level of access to that record, the record no longer appears in their accounts. The Service deletes the record from all users. We wait 90 days before permanently deleting the record information in order to help avoid accidental or malicious removal of your health information. 

### Deleting health information

When a Program or person moves a piece of health information to the trash, custodians may still view it there, and can restore it or delete it permanently from there at any time. Please note that Programs and non-custodial persons with whom you have shared your information are not able to see or restore items in the trash, nor may they permanently delete health information.   
Permanently deleting health information removes it from the trash. Once someone permanently deletes an item, we cannot restore it. The Service adds an entry in your record history noting the name of the person who permanently deleted information and the date the deletion occurred. 

### E-mail controls

To keep you informed of the latest improvements, the Service may send you a newsletter. You can choose whether to receive newsletters when you sign up for the Service, or unsubscribe at any time.   
The service will periodically send you an email summarizing recent account activity. If you do not want to receive these emails, you can unsubscribe at any time 

### Use of our services

mTatva uses qualified professional to digitize your prescription but human errors can happen. mTatva is not responsible for such errors. You would need to verify data on our service on web and mobile, SMS, emails and paper with your original records. All services given including the personalized information is best prepared with medical professionals but that can not be considered as medical advise. The information provided is for increasing awareness but do not replace or suffice for medical advise. Please consult your provider for further information. 

### Security of your personal information

mTatva is committed to protecting the security of your personal information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use, and disclosure. For example, we store the personal information you provide on computer servers with limited access that are located in controlled facilities.   
Additionally: 

  * The Service sends all communications (except e-mail sent outside of mTatva Message Center) using encryption.
  * You can view a history of access and actions to any Health Record of which you are a custodian.

### Disclaimer About Medical Information:

The information and reference materials contained here are intended solely for the general information of the reader. It is not to be used for treatment purposes, but rather for discussion with the patient's own physician. The information presented here is not intended to diagnose health problems or to take the place of professional medical care. The information contained herein is neither intended to dictate what constitutes reasonable, appropriate or best care for any given health issue, nor is it intended to be used as a substitute for the independent judgment of a physician for any given health issue. All content, including text, graphics, images and information, contained on or available through this web site is for general information purposes only. The major limitation of informational resources on mTatva is the inability to take into account the unique circumstances that define the health issues of the patient. If you have persistent health problems or if you have further questions, please consult your health care provider. All visitors to mTatva and associated web sites agree to read and abide by the complete terms of this agreement.   
The information posted here by mTatva is not to be considered medical advice and is not intended to replace consultation with a qualified medical professional. 

### Use of cookies

We use cookies with this Service to enable you to sign in and to help personalize the Service. A cookie is a small text file that a web page server places on your hard disk. It is not possible to use cookies to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. A Web server assigns cookies uniquely to you and only a Web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you can read the cookies.   
One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. For example, if you personalize a Web page, or navigate within a site, a cookie helps the site to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. Using cookies simplifies the process of delivering relevant content, eases site navigation, and so on. When you return to the Web site, you can retrieve the information you previously provided, so you can easily use the site's features that you customized.   
You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline some or all cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline all cookies, you may not be able to use interactive features of this or other Web sites that depend on cookies.
